East.
Too bad. I thought if you was heading north
I might be able to help you out.
I m pushing myself late tonight.
I don t like to ride alone at night.
I am one of those guys who gotta talk
or I fall asleep.
My partner, he s got Lou to keep him company, but ...
... I ain t got nobody at all.
- Where re you coming from?
- West.
Yeah sure, I know, but ...
... where? LA?
- Maybe.
- I ve got a cousin out in LA ...
- You don t say.
- Yeah. He s been out ...
You're not much of a talker, are you?
My mother taught me never to speak
to strangers.
- Oh, wise guy is it.
- So what!?
Okay, okay. Don t get sore.
Trying to be sociable. That s all.
Hey, Grandma!
Give me change for a dime, will you?.
Let s have something quieter this time, Joe.
My head s splitting.
It that what's wrong with it?
Done with your coffee?
No.
And don t rush me, will you?
Hey, turn that off.
Will you turn that thing off?
- What s eating you now?
- Yeah, what s eating you?
- That music, it stinks.
- Oh, you don t like it, huh?
- No. Turn it off!
- Now wait a minute, pal.
That was mine, that penny.
This is a free country,
and I play whatever I want to.
OK.
Sure, and if you don t like it,
you don t have to listen to it.
And you can leave here any time, you want to.
OK OK. I m sorry I am.
First good piece played tonight,
and you don t like it.
Some people just ain t got any good taste.
That tune...  That tune...
Why was it always that rotten tune?
Following me around, beating in my head,
never letting up.