Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Subtitles by DHM
Well, here we are. I turn down here
at the next block.
Thanks, mister. I'll get off there.
- Want anything else?
- No.
Hey, you!
- Me?
- Yeah you. Where re you heading?
East.
Too bad. I thought if you was heading north
I might be able to help you out.
I m pushing myself late tonight.
I don t like to ride alone at night.
I am one of those guys who gotta talk
or I fall asleep.
My partner, he s got Lou to keep him company, but ...
... I ain t got nobody at all.
- Where re you coming from?
- West.
Yeah sure, I know, but ...
... where? LA?
- Maybe.
- I ve got a cousin out in LA ...
- You don t say.
- Yeah. He s been out ...
You're not much of a talker, are you?
My mother taught me never to speak
to strangers.
- Oh, wise guy is it.
- So what!?
Okay, okay. Don t get sore.
Trying to be sociable. That s all.
Hey, Grandma!
Give me change for a dime, will you?.
Let s have something quieter this time, Joe.
My head s splitting.
It that what's wrong with it?
Done with your coffee?
No.
And don t rush me, will you?
Hey, turn that off.
Will you turn that thing off?
- What s eating you now?
- Yeah, what s eating you?
- That music, it stinks.
- Oh, you don t like it, huh?
- No. Turn it off!
- Now wait a minute, pal.
That was mine, that penny.
This is a free country,
and I play whatever I want to.
OK.
Sure, and if you don t like it,
you don t have to listen to it.
And you can leave here any time, you want to.
OK OK. I m sorry I am.
First good piece played tonight,
and you don t like it.
Some people just ain t got any good taste.
That tune...  That tune...
Why was it always that rotten tune?
Following me around, beating in my head,
never letting up.
Did you ever want to forget anything?
Did you ever want cut away a piece of your memory
or blot it out?
You can t, you know.
No matter how hard you try.
You can change the scenery ...
... but sooner or later,
you ll get a whiff of perfume or...
... somebody will say a certain phrase,
or maybe hum something ...
... and you re licked again.
"I can t believe that you re in love with me
I used to love that song, once.
So did the customers back in the old
Break O  Dawn Club in New York.
I can t remember a night when I didn t get
at least 3 requests for it.
Sue ...
She was always was selling it too.
Those were the days.
Your eyes of blue, your kisses too
I never knew what they could do
I can't believe that you're in love with me
You're telling everyone I know
That I'm on your mind each place you go
They can't believe that you're in love with me.
I have always placed you far above me
I just can't imagine that you love me
And after all is said and done
To think that I'm the lucky one
I can't believe that you're in love with me.
It wasn t much of a club, really.
You know the kind.
A joint where you could have a sandwich
and a few drinks ...
... and run interference for your girl
on the dance floor.
I fronted the piano in there every night
from 8:00 until the place closed up ...
... which usually meant 4:00 in the morning.
A good job, as jobs went in those days.
And then too ...
... there was Sue.
... who made working there a little like working in heaven.
But how we felt about each other.
Well, there was nothing very unusual in that.
I was an ordinary healthy guy,
and she was an ordinary healthy girl.
And when you add those two together,
you get an ordinary healthy romance.
Which is the old story ...
... sure, but somehow ...
... the most wonderful thing in the world.
All in all, I was a pretty lucky guy.
Mr Paderewsky, I presume ...
It's beautiful.
You re going to make Carnegie Hall your door.
Yeah, as a janitor.
I ll make my debut in the basement.
I don t blame you for being bitter, darling but ...
... you mustn t give up hope.
- Why, some day ...
- Yeah, some day ...
... if I don t get arthritis first.
In the meantime, let s blow this trap.
- Like to get something to eat, hon ?
- I don t think so, Al.
I lose my appetite working in this fleabag.
- Let's go home.
- OK.
I can t stand much more of that dump.
Did you see that drunk tonight trying to paw me.
No, what drunk?
It doesn t matter what drunk!
Say, what s the matter with you tonight, darling?
That s the third time you started
to tell me something and then stopped.
We shouldn t have any secrets from each other, Sue.
Next week, we re going to make with the ring and
the license. You and me. We ll be a team.
Yes, that's right. In the Bush League.
- I don t get you.
- We ve been struck out.
A funny way to talk, darling.
- Don t you want to marry me?
- Al, look, I love you, you know I do.
- And I want to marry you.
- But ...
But not now.
Only after we do good.
Someday, I'm going away.
Oh, I know you ll think it silly ...
That s why I hesitated to tell you.
But I m going to California ...
I want to try my luck in Hollywood.
That s the most stupid thing, I ever heard of.
Don t you know millions of people go out there
every year and wind up polishing cuspidors?
I thought you had better sense.
You sound as if you don t think I have any talent.
That has nothing to do with it.
- I'll make out alright.
- Maybe. But what about me?
Doesn t it mean anything to you that
you re busting up all our plans.
- We may not see each other for years.
- It won t be that long.
- I thought you loved me.
- I do, you know I do.
Well ... here we are.
Al ...
Al, why can t you see my side of it?
I'm young. We both are.
And we ve got all the time in the world to settle down.
Really, darling ...
... what I m doing is the only sane thing to do.
I ...
I hate the thought of being so far away from you, but ...
But we'll be together again someday.
Maybe you ll decide to come out too, later on.
So long.
Al ...
Aren t you going to kiss me goodnight?
Sure, why not?
Good night.
Say Roberts, you hit the jackpot this time ...
Ten bucks.
Thanks.
But when a drunk handed me a ten spot,
after a request ...
... I couldn t get very excited.
What was it? I asked myself.
A piece of paper crawling with germs.
It couldn t buy anything I wanted.
It couldn t ...
Then I thought of something.
Long distance.
I d like to put a call through to Los Angeles.
Miss Harvey, Sue Harvey. H-A-R-V-E-Y.
The number is: Crest View 65723.
Fifty ... seventy five ... eighty five.
Hello Sue? This is Al.
Oh baby, it s great to hear from you too.
What s that? You do?
Oh, me too, darling.
I thought I d go batty without you.
I just had to ...
Huh? ... You re working as a hash slinger?
Gee honey, that s tough.
Those guys out in Hollywood don t know the real thing
when it s right in front of them.
You just stick it out too, baby.
Keep going around to those casting offices.
I m sure you ll click.
Look, I ll tell you what. You stay put out there.
I'll come to you.
No, do not try to stop me.
Just expect me.
Train? Who knows. Train, plane, bus, magic carpet.
I'll be there if I have to crawl.
If I have to travel by pogo stick.
And then ...
... let s get married right away, huh?
That s the stuff.
That's what I ve been wanting to hear you say.
Well ... goodbye for now.
I ll be seeing you soon.
Yeah.
Bye.
The only way I could cross country was to thumb rides.
For even after hawking everything,
I only had enough money to eat.
Money. You know what that is.
The stuff you never have enough of.
Little green things with ...
... George Washington s picture
that men slave for ...
... commit crimes for, die for.
It s the stuff that has caused more
trouble in the world ...
... than anything else we ever invented.
Simply because, there s too little of it.
At least, I had too little of it.
So it was me for the thumb.
Ever done any hitchhiking?
It's not much fun, believe me.
Oh yeah, I know all about how it s an education ...
... how to get to meet a lot of people
and all that. But me ...
... from now on, I ll take my education
in college, or in PS-62, or I ll...
... send $ 1.98 in stamps for  Ten Easy Lessons .
Thumbing rides may save your busfare,
but it s dangerous.
You never know what s in store for you,
when you hear the...
... squeal of brakes.
If only I had known what I was getting into,
that day in Arizona.
Here, throw that in the back seat.
Okay, let s go. Make sure that door s closed.
You know, Emily Post ought to write a ...
... book of rules for guys thumbing rides.
Because, as it is now, you never know
what s right and what s wrong.
We rode along for a little while, neither one
of us saying anything.
I was glad of that.
I never know what to say to strange people
driving cars.
Then too, you can never tell if a guy wants to talk.
A lot of rides have been cut short
because of a big mouth.
So I kept my mouth shut until
he started opening up.
Hand me that little box in the compartment,
will ya pal.
Hold the wheel, will you.
- How far are you going?
- L.A.
Well, you re really travelling, aren t you?
Yeah, but I don t expect to make it
for a couple of years ...
... at the rate I ve been sporting rides.
- Not much luck, huh?
- Sure, all bad.
Not many people stop for a guy these days.
Afraid of a stick up, maybe.
Well, you can t blame them.
- Where are you coming from?
- New York.
Well, New York!
Well, you re in luck this time.
I m going all the way.
Right through to Los Angeles.
- You drive a car?
- Sure, if you re tired, let me know.
I ll holla.
I guess at least an hour passed before
I noticed ...
... those deep scratches
in his right hand.
They were wicked.
Three puffy red lines, about a quarter
of an inch apart.
He must have seen me looking at them,
because he said ...
Beauties, aren t they?
They re going to be scars some day.
What an animal!
Whatever it was, it must have been
pretty big and vicious to have done that.
Right on both counts, New York.
I was tussling with the most dangerous animal
In the world...
... a woman.
Must have been Tarzan s mate.
Looks like, you lost the bout.
It certainly wasn t a draw.
You know, there should be a law
against dangerous claws.
Yeah.
I tossed her out of the car on her ear.
Was I wrong?
Give a lift to a tomato, you expect her
to be nice, don t you?
- Yeah.
- After all, what kind of a dame, thumbs rides?
- Sunday school teacher?
- Yeah.
A little witch.
Must have thought, she was riding
with some fall guy.
Not me who s been booking horses around race tracks,
since I was twenty.
Ahh, I've known a million dames like her.
- Two million.
- Yeah.
Stopped the car, opened the door ...
"Take another hour and stop here, sister", I told her.
- That s the stuff
- As I was going on.
If you want to see a real scar, brother,
get a load of this.
Wow
- I got that one duelling.
- Duelling?
Yeah, just kidding of course.
My dad owned a couple of Franco-Prussian sabres.
Kept them on the wall for decoration.
Well one day, another kid and I took them down,
and the old man wasn t around... Had a duel.
He hit me in the arm here.
Pretty mean cut. Infection set in later.
Yeah, I can see that.
- Oh, give me that box again, will ya.
- Yeah.
Pain made me lose my head, I guess...
Began slashing ...
Before I knew it, I d put the other kid s eye out.
That was tough.
Oh, it was just an accident, of course.
You know how kids are.
I got scared and decided I was going to
run away from home.
Old man almost caught me, when I was
packing my duds.
The bloody rag I had wrapped around my wrist
hadn't caught his attention ...
... he'd have seen the bundle for sure.
So I beat it, when he was phoning for a doctor.
That was fifteen   sixteen years ago.
I haven t been home since.
Pull in there for a bite of something, huh?
I ll buy you ...
Brother, was I hungry.
I hadn t had anything in my stomach for hours.
But even with that gnawing in the pit of my belly.
I didn t want to be in too big a rush
to put on the feed bag.
First, I had to make sure this guy knew the score.
If I got him down on me, goodbye ticket to Hollywood.
- I ll wait out here for you, mister.
- If it s the money, don t worry about paying for it.
This time it s on me.
- Well, that s quite ...
- Haskell. Think nothing of it.
You make your first million, maybe you can
do the same for me. Come on, New York.
I gotta make the West Coast by Wednesday.
There s a horse running at Santa Anita,
named "Paradisical" ...
- Means dough to for me, if I m on it.
- You ll make it, alright
He did most of the talking, during the half hour
we were in the place.
I ate.
He rambled on about his old man, whom he hadn t
heard from since he ran away as a kid,...
... and how he happened to become a bookie.
And then all about how he got rooked in Miami.
One race, 38 grand. They cleaned out my book.
- How do you like that?
- It was tough luck.
Yeah, and I'm supposed to be the smart guy.
You just wait ...
I m going back to Florida, next season,
with all kinds of jack.
And you watch those stinkers run for cover.
- Want anything else?
- No thanks, I've had plenty.
Got the cheque there, sister?
Oh, just a minute! Your change, sir.
- Keep it, sister.
- Oh, thank you, sir. Call again.
I ll be waiting outside for you,
when you ve finished work.
Sharp chick, huh?
I drove all that night, while Haskell
slept like a log.
After a while, I began to get sleepy myself.
I was happy though.
Soon I d be with Sue again.
The long trip was practically over, and there d be
no more hoofing it down the concrete.
I began to think of the future ...
... which couldn t have been brighter
if I d embroidered it with neon lights.
It was nice to think of Sue, shooting to the top.
Hmpf ... It s amazing what a full belly can do
to your imagination.
Your eyes of blue, your kisses too
I never knew what they could do
I can't believe that you're in love with me
You're telling everyone I know
I'm on your mind each place you go
I can't believe that you're in love with me