At least, they know they re done for.
They don t have to sweat blood wondering if they are.
Your philosophy stinks, pal.
We all know we re going to kick off some day.
It s only a question of when.
What got us on this subject anyway?
We ll be discussing politics, next.
Yeah.
Where d you hide the butts?
On the table, sucker.
We are bored each other with conversation
for a couple of hours longer.
Every five minutes, one of us was wishing
we had another bottle ...
... or a radio, or something to read.
Then finally, we ended ran out of chatter.
I know it s only eleven o clock,
but I want to get up early ...
... and make the rounds of the used car lots.
Don t worry about that
we got all the time in the world.
Maybe you have, but if you think I want ...
... to stay cooped up in this place any longer
than I have to, you're batty.
It s not a bad place.
You pay plenty for digs like this in New York.
I wouldn t like it, if it was the Ritz.
Rotten liquor.
You got a mean cough. You want to do
something about it.
I ll be alright.
That's what Camille said.
- Who?
- Nobody you know.
- Wasn t that the dame that died of consumption
- Yes.
Wouldn t it be a break for you, if I did kick off.
You d be free with old Haskell s stolen car.
I don t want to see anybody die.
Not even me?
Specially, not you. One person died on me.
If you did. Well, that s all I need.
You don t like me, do you Roberts?
Like you? I love you.
My favourite sport is being kept prisoner.
After we sell the car, you can go to blazes
for all I care.
But not until then.
I'm going to bed.
Goodnight, Roberts.
Don t try and sneak away during the night.
All doors are locked.
Anyway, I find you gone in the morning ...
... I ll notify the police.
- They ll pick you up.
- Don t worry, I know when I m in a spot.
Well, good night.
I hope that that portable rack
isn't too uncomfortable for you.
Don t lose any sleep over it, will you Vera?
Crest View 6-5-7-2-3
Hello? Hello?
No. Not yet, darling.
Tomorrow ... maybe.
If this were fiction, I would fall in love with Vera.
Marry her and make a respectable woman of her.
Or else, she would make some supreme, Class A
sacrifice for me ...
... and die.
Sue and I would bawl a little over her grave ...
... and make some crack about there s good
in all of us.
But Vera, unfortunately, was just as rotten in the morning ...
... as she d been the night before.
Alright alright, I'm coming.
Look Vera, it's almost noon.
So what? The dealers will be there all day.
They ll be there all year too,
but we don t have to wait that long.
Shut up. You re making like a husband.
- Well, do I rate a whistle?
- You sure do, but let s go.
Let s go, let s go. I spend $85 and two hours
preparing bait ...
... and all you can say is, "Let s go .
Come on.
We passed a few used car lots last night down this way.
What do you think we can get for this heap?
I don t know. Plenty. Just let me handle everything.
Think you can get two thousand dollars?
I don t know. But don t worry ...
I ll squeeze as much out of this guy, as I can.
If I let it go cheap without a fight,
he might think we ve stolen the car.
And listen, don t make any slips and call me Roberts.
That ll cook us.
I don t need you to tell me that.
You better just sit by and keep your mouth closed.
Remember we re both in the soup,
if anything happens ...
- Forget it and drive.
- You re my wife, Vera Haskell.
Look, after the deal s closed ...
... let s go back to that place
on Hollywood Boulevard ...
... where I saw the fur jacket.
I want to buy it.
After the deal s closed, I m saying goodbye to you.
That s right, I forgot.
I guess I'm getting kind of used to you.
Well that s a habit you can start breaking.
Let's try this place in the middle of the block.
Good afternoon, what can I do for you?
- We re interested in selling a car.
- If the price is right.
Well, if it s in good mechanical condition,
it should bluebook for about $1600.
Tony, take a look at this motor.
Sixteen hundred, are you kidding?
Well, maybe $1850.
Before I let it go for $1850, I ll wreck it
and collect the insurance first.
Lady, this motor s seen a lot of driving.
While the mechanic inspected the car we haggled.
At last, when we were all worn out
we hit a compromise ...
... his price.
- OK, it s a deal.
- Right, come in and we ll sign the papers.
I have the ownership papers right here with me.
Look Vera, in the meantime, will you clean out
the ash compartment.
- Maybe there s some stuff in it.
- Alright, darling.
1850 bucks, that dirty crook.
- Hmm, New York, huh?
- Yup.
- But you bought the car in Miami.
- Yes.
Well, let s see about the insurance, we can either
have it transferred or cancelled.
Ah, what kind of insurance do you have, Mr. Haskell?
Well ah ...
... aren t all the papers there?
I don t see any.
Surely you know what type of insurance
you carry on the car.
The name of the company?
Yeah, but ...
Well, if you ll just tell me the name of the company ...
- ... I'd be very glad to take care of all the details.
- Well ...
- Did you sign the papers yet?
- Not yet.
Well don t. We re not selling the car.
- Well, wait a minute, Mrs Haskell.
- Come on darling.
- What s the matter? Change your mind?
- Yes, I m sorry, I guess I have.
- But, Vera ...
- Let s go.
You got me out of a tight spot Vera,
but I still don t understand all this.
You will in a minute.
I almost threw away a gold mine.
$1850 isn t to be sneezed at.
The car doesn t book for as much as I thought.
- We re not selling the car.
- You want to keep it?
Now wait a minute, Vera, you said yourself
I wouldn t be safe ...
... until the car was in someone else s name.
I d like to be free of this mess, when I go.
That's just it, Robert, you re not going.
There s a drive in at the corner.
Pull in there and we ll get a bite to eat ...
... and, I ll explain.
What is this - another one of your brilliant ideas?
- Hello, may I take your order?
- Make mine, a ham sandwich and coffee.
- And for you sir?
- Oh, I don t care ... the same.
Thank you.
Get this, Vera.
I've been pretty patient, so far.
- I ve done everything you asked me to do, but no more.
- Shut up!
We ve taken Haskell s money ...
You can have the dough we get from
selling the car ...
... but you re not going to keep me a prisoner.
It s a good thing I bought the paper.
Take a look at that.
- Vera, I m in no mood ...
- Read that!
- No.
- Yes.
- No, I won t do it.
- Yes, you will.
You think I'm crazy? It's impossible I tell you.
Excuse me.
Blow the horn when you re through.
No one could possibly get away with an act like that.
They d be wise to me in a minute
Don t be yellow.
You look enough like him.
The same colouring and the same build.
See how his clothes fit?
I m not kidding. You almost had me fooled for a while.
Oh, grow up, Vera.
Don t you think a father knows his own son?
And there must be other relatives.
The father won t have to know you.
We ll wait till he gives up the ghost.
He s an old geezer and he won t pull through.
And as far as the relatives are concerned ...
They haven t seen you in fifteen or twenty years.
- Eat.
- I m not hungry ...
And I won t do it.
It's not as tough as it sounds.
Remember, you ve...
... got all kinds of identification: his car,
letters, license ...
I could never get away with it.
It's the stupidest thing I ve ever heard.
The old boy has bags of dough.
Look in the paper there ...
Personal fortune assessed over fifteen million.
He ll leave plenty, I tell you.
Maybe he cut off his son. How do we know?
It's out, Vera. I won t have anything to do with it.
I think you will.
Look Vera, I'll do anything within reason.
But not that. So forget it.
Find yourself another stooge.
You re sick.
You d be fixed for the rest of your life as Charlie Haskell.
You can take your inheritance and go away.
No more worrying about the rent, no sweating ...
... scheming, wondering where your next meal s
coming from. Think about that, Roberts.
Vera, please. You re talking too loud.
Unless I m splitting 50-50 with you? Sure. Why not?
- We re both alike, both born the same guy.
- Take it easy, Vera.
People around here are going to hear you talk.
We ll wait until we read old man Haskell s dead.
Then you show up.
Like you read in New York that he was sick.
No.
- Suppose he doesn t die?
- He will, I know he will. Something tells me.
But as much as I insisted, I would have no part
of her scheme.
Vera was taking it for granted, I would.
Neither of us had our minds on the cards
as we played that night.
I knew we were just trying to kill time
between newspaper editions.
This was a death watch, for Vera.
Maybe it was for me too.
Don t you realise, if I m caught, they ll want to know
where I got the car and stuff.
- And they ll have me on a murder charge.
- If you re smart, you won t get caught.
I m out for seven.
If I m caught, don t you realise you'll be out too?
18 points. That gives me 30.
How will I be out?
You ll be out $1850, you would have gotten on the car.
Really Vera, you ll be an awful chump.
You threw away all that dough on a dizzy long shot.
Let me sell the bus tomorrow. With the money
it ll bring and...
... what you ve already got a clever kid like you
could run it up in no time.
- And we d both be in the clear.
- I ll be in the clear anyway.
Maybe. Maybe.
But if I got caught ...
- I d get good and sore too, you know.
- You mean you d squeal?
- Well no, not squeal exactly
- Never mind what you meant.
Even if you did tell the cops, I was in on it
with you ...
... what could they do to me?
They might give me the same medicine they gave you.
- Yeah.
- A rope.
But I'm on my way now.
All they d be doing would be rushing it.
Alright, but think of the $1850 you d lose
You d kick yourself around the block,
if you let it get away from you.
I ll take the chance.
- Want another drink?
- You being a goon.
That s the way people wind up behind the eight ball ...
Once they get a few dollars, they become greedy
and want more.
- More. More.
- Caesar.
- Who?
- You know, that Roman general.
He got his, for being greedy.
He wasn t satisfied, so the final wind up was
he took the count.
A couple of days ago, you didn t have a dime.
Why you were so broke, you couldn t pay
cash for a postage stamp.
Now you ve got almost $700, with $1850 in the offing.
- Take my advice, don t try for more!
- I m tired of this game.
- Let's have some black jack.
- Play solitaire!
OK I will, if that s the way you feel about it.
That s the way I feel about it.
Getting sore and throwing things won t help much, Roberts.
I m really doing you a favour.
I help you out of a jam by keeping my mouth shut.
I show you how to make some soft money,
and what thanks do I get.
- Thanks?!
- Sure, or would you rather I called the cops ...
... and tell them you killed the man
and stole his money.
- I didn t kill anybody.
- Yes, you did.
No, I didn t. You know I didn t.
Alright, then.
Suppose I call the cops ...
If you're innocent, what have you got to be scared of?
OK, call them, if you must.
Go ahead, call them. See if I care.
At least they ll give me a square deal.
- You want me to call them?
- You heard me. But I m warning you ...
If I m pinched, I ll swear you were in on it.
I ll say that you helped me.
- If I fry, I ll get even with you.
- You wouldn t dare, you re chicken!
Yeah? Then try it and see.
Call them. Yeah.
Okay I will.
Information?
I want the number of the Hollywood police station.
OK, I got it. Thanks.
Wait a minute, Vera, you wouldn t do that.
Oh, wouldn t I? Let me do it, and I ll show you
if I would.
Take it easy. Now let's talk this over.
This was early in the evening.
And the conversation while hectic was at least pitched low.
But as the minutes passed ...
... and more obstacles to her plan
popped into in my head ...
... the air got blue.
Each word coming from our lips cracked like a whip.
I reminded her that as Charles Haskell,
I didn t even know my mother s name ...
... where I d gone to school,
the name of my best friend ...
... whether I had an Aunt Emma or not,
my religion ...
... and if I d ever owned a dog.
I didn t even know what my middle initial stood for.
I also pointed out that the real Haskell
had a scar on his forearm.
His people never saw that scar.
You told me he ran away right after putting out
the kid s eye.
Yeah, but his father knew he was cut.
- There d be some kind of a mark.
- So what?
The old man s dead or will be, I hope,
by tomorrow morning s papers.
Anyway, you could cut yourself a little, couldn t you?
Boy, for that kind of dough, I d let you
cut my leg off.
You're drunk and you re crazy mad, Vera.
Turn me in, if you want to,
but I won t get mixed up in this.
Besides, how do we know? Haskell was such a phony.
Maybe he wasn t the man s son after all.
Maybe he just dreamed it up.
Well, dreaming or not ...
... you won t be dreaming
when the law taps you on the shoulder.
There s a cute little gas chamber
waiting for you, Roberts.
And I hear extradition to Arizona s a cinch.
Where's that phone?
- Vera!
- Leave me alone.
- I want a phone call, police.
I hate you, you stinking ...
You leave me alone!
I'll let you alone when you promise
to leave the phone where it is.
You re drunk. You don t know what you re doing
- You're hurting me,
- Will you promise?
Alright.
You hurt me.
- I'm sorry, but ...
- It's hot in here, open up the window!
- It s not hot.
- Don t tell me. Now do you do it or do I do it?
- You're no gentleman, see?
- Yeah.
Alright, I'll open up the window.
Vera!
Vera, open the door. Please open the door.
Vera, open the door. Don t use the phone.
Listen to me.
I don t like you, Roberts.
You're no gentleman, see. You hurt my hand.
And I m going to get even with you.
You don t open the door, I m going to kick it down, Vera.
Vera, don t call the cops. Listen to me.
I ll do anything you say.
Vera, let me in.
I ll break the phone!
Vera ...
The world is full of sceptics.
I know - I'm one myself.
In the Haskell business, how many of you would believe
he fell out of the car?
And now, after killing Vera without
really meaning to do it.
How many of you would believe it wasn t premeditated.
In a jury room, every last man of you would go down
shouting that ...
... she had me over a barrel and my only out was force.
The room was still.
So quiet that for a while I wondered
if I had suddenly gone deaf.
It was pure fear of course.
And I was hysterical.
But without making a sound.
Vera was dead
and I was her murderer.
Murderer!
What an awful word that is.
But I had become one.
I d better not get caught.
What evidence there was around the place
had to be destroyed.
And from the looks of things, there was plenty.
Looking around the room, at the things we d bought ...
... was like looking into the faces of a hundred
people, who had seen us together and who remembered me.
This was the kind of testimony, I couldn t rub out.
No. I could burn clothes and hide bottles ...
... for the next five years.
There d always be witnesses.
The landlady for one. She could identify me.
The car dealer, the waitress in the drive-in,
the girl in the dress shop and ...
... the guy in the liquor store.
They could all identify me.
I was cooked. Done for. I had to get out of there.
While once I had remained beside a dead body ...
... planning carefully how to avoid being
accused of killing him ...
... this time I couldn t.
This time I was guilty.
I knew it.
Felt it.
I was like a guy suffering from shock.
Things were whirling around in my head.
I couldn t make myself think right.
All I could think of was the guy with the saxophone
and what he was playing.
It wasn t a love song.
It was a dirge.
But my problems weren t solved.
I had to stay away from New York for all time.
Because Al Roberts was listed as dead,
and had to stay dead.
And I could never to go back to Hollywood.
Someone might recognize me as Haskell ...
Then too, there was Sue ...
I could never go to her with a thing like this
hanging over my head.
All I could do was pray she d be happy.
I was in Bakersfield, before I read that Vera s body
was discovered ...
... and that the police were looking for Haskell
in connection with his wife s murder.
Isn t that a laugh?
Haskell got me into this mess, and
Haskell was getting me out of it.
The police were searching for a dead man.
I keep trying to forget what happened ...
... and wonder what my life might have been, if that
car of Haskell s hadn t stopped.
But one thing, I don t have to wonder about.
I know ...
... someday a car will stop to pick me up
that I never thumbed.
Yes. Fate ... or some mysterious force ...
... can put the finger on you or me ...
... for no good reason at all.
Subtitles by DHM
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player