Mister Haskell.
Mister Haskell, wake up. It's raining.
Don t you think we ought to stop
and put up the top?
Mister Haskell, I m going to put up the top.
So far, things had been my way ...
... but from then on something else
stepped in and shunted me off ...
... to a different destination than
the one I picked for myself ...
... for when I pulled open that door ...
Mr Haskell, what s the matter?
Are you hurt?
Are you hurt, Mr Haskell?
Doubtless ... I ll listen to it.
... but I know what you re going to hand me
even before you open your mouth.
You re going to tell me you don t believe my story
about Haskell died ...
... and give me that "don t make me laugh"
expression on your smug faces.
I saw at once he was dead ...
and I was in for it.
Who would believe that he fell out of the car?
Why if Haskell came to, which of course he couldn t,
even he would swear ...
... I conked him over the head for his dough.
Yes, I was in for it.
Instinct told me to run, but then
I realised it was hopeless.
There were lots of people back down the road
who could identify me.
That gas station guy and the waitress.
I would be in a worse spot then,
trying to explain why I beat it.
The next possibility was to sit tight and
tell the truth when the cops came.
But that would be crazy. They d laugh at
the truth, and I d have my head in a noose.
So what else was there to do, but hide the body
and get away in the car?
I couldn t leave the car there with him in the gully.
That would be like erecting a tombstone.
My idea was to cover him with brush, not to rob him.
But then I remembered that even if I only drove
the car for a hundred miles or so ...
... I would need money for gas.
Besides, it was stupid of me
to leave all that money on a dead man.
Not only that. I d have to take his drivers license
in case I was stopped or something.
I didn t like to think about it, but by that time
I d done just what the police would say I did ...
... even if I didn t.
My clothes. The owner of such an expensive car
would never be wearing them.
Some cop might pull me in under suspicion.
Hey you, this your car?
Don t you know better than to leave a car with
the wheels half way in the middle of the road?
That s the way accidents happen.
I ... I m sorry officer. I was just putting up my top.
- I didn t think.
- Well, the next time think.
I ll let you go now,
but watch your step in the future.
I know that's a lonely stretch, but cars come by here
once and a while, and ...
... we have plenty of crack ups.
Thanks officer.
I left nothing in the car that would
give me away as Roberts.
If they found a dead man in the gully now,
it would be me.
As I drove off, it was still raining ...
... and the drops streaked down the windshield
like tears.
I kept imagining I was being followed and
that I could hear sirens back in the distance.
Just how long it took me to cover
the 60 odd miles to the California state line ...
... I don t know.
I lost all track of time.
But the rain had stopped and the sun was up
when I pulled up to the inspection station.
- Hello. Carrying any fruits or vegetables?
- No.
- Any livestock or poultry?
I d like to see your registration and
and driver's license, please.
- Anything in the baggage compartment?
- Just baggage.
Charles Haskell Jr, age 30,
brown eyes, dark hair ...
... identifying marks, none.
- Are you Charles Haskell Jr?
- Yes.
Well, remember that if you re employed
and stay over than 30 days ...
... you take out California plates.
Alright officer, but I'll only be in the
state a short while.
Right, you can go now.
I couldn t drive any further without any sleep.
Cops or no cops ...
... I knew I had to hit the hay and hit it hard.
I was dead tired.
No ... No you can t, Mr Haskell.
No.
Mr Haskell, you can t die.
They ll think ... that I did it.
No, Mr Haskell. No ... no.
- Who s there?
- It s the maid. Can I can come in and clean?
Later.
- In a half hour.
- Alright, sir.
There was no time to lose.
Every minute I had to be Charles Haskell was dangerous.
And I d have to be Charles Haskell, until I got
to some city ...
... where I could leave the car and be swallowed up.
That meant driving the car as far as San Bernardino ...
... maybe even to Los Angeles.
In a little town, I might be noticed ...
... but in a city, I should be safe enough.
Then after I ditched the car, I could go on to Sue.
But those five minutes at the state line ...
... made me realise, it might be a good idea
to find out a little bit about Mr Haskell.
Then if anyone asked me questions
I could give the right answers.
The first thing I found out was
that I had $768.
This was a lot of jack. But believe me ...
... it was the kind of money
I d rather not have.
And then I found out from a letter
Haskell was carting around in his bag ...
... that he wasn t the open-handed
easy going big shot ...
... who went around buying dinners for strange
hitchhikers.
Before I got done reading it, I saw him more
as a chiseller.
It was written to his old man in California ...
... the one he hadn t seen in so many years.
In it Haskell posed as a salesman ...
... of hymnals, of all things.
It was easy to see where Haskell expected
to raise the new stake ...
... for his book in Miami.
By rooking his old man.
That was about all I found out from his effects ...
... and it was enough.
I told myself maybe old man Haskell
was lucky his son kicked off.
He would never know it, but it saved him from taking
a flyer on sacred literature preferred.
Near the airport of Desert Centre,
I pulled up for water.
There was a woman.
Hey you! Come on, if you want a ride.
- How far are you going?
That took me by surprise, and I turned
turned my head to look her over.
She was facing straight ahead,
so I couldn t see her eyes.
But she was young, not more than 24.
Man, she looked as if she d just been thrown off
the crummiest freight train in the world.
Yet in spite of this, I got the impression of beauty.
Not the beauty of a movie actress, mind you ...
... or the beauty you dream about when
you're with your wife.
But a natural beauty.
A beauty that s almost homely, because it s so real.
Then suddenly she turned to face me.
- How far did you say we re going?
- Los Angeles.
L.A.? ... L.A s good enough for me, mister
- That s what I was afraid of.
- What did you say?
Oh nothing. Just thinking out loud.
People get in trouble for doing that.
- What s your name?
- You can call me Vera, if you like.
- Do you live in Los Angeles?
- No.
- Where are you coming from?
- Oh, back there.
- Needles?
- No.
Oh sure, Phoenix.
You look just like a Phoenix girl.
Are the girls in Phoenix that bad?
The girl must have been pretty tired,
because she fell asleep ...
... not twenty minutes after she stepped
into the car.
She lay sprawled out with her head resting
against the far door like Haskell.
I didn t like that part of it much
but I didn t wake her up.
It wasn t that this girl still worried me.
I d gotten over that funny feeling I had,
when she looked at me ...
... which I put down as just my jangled nerves.
With her eyes closed, and the tempest gone out of them
She seemed harmless enough.
Instead of disliking her, I began to feel sorry for her.
The poor kid probably had had a rough time of it.
Who was she anyway?
And why was she going to Los Angeles?
And where d she come from in the first place.
The only thing I knew about her was her name.
Not that it made any difference.
A few hours more, we d be in Hollywood.
I d forget where I parked the car
and look up Sue.
This nightmare of being a dead man would be over.
Who this dame was, well it was no business of mine.
Where did you leave his body?
Where did you leave the owner of this car?
You re not fooling anyone.
This buggy belongs to a guy named Haskell.
That's not you, mister.
You're out of your mind, that's my name,
Charles Haskell. I can prove it.
- My driver s license.
- Save yourself the trouble, mister.
Having Haskell s wallet only makes it worse.
It just so happens I rode with Charlie Haskell
all the way from Louisiana.
He picked me up outside of Shreveport.
- You rode ...
- You heard me.
Then it all came back to me.
All the talk about duelling and scars and scratches.
There was no doubt about it.
Vera must be the woman Haskell had mentioned.
She must have passed me while I slept.
Well? ... Well, I'm waiting.
My goose was cooked. She had me.
That Haskell guy wasn t dead yet.
He wasn t stretched out stiff and cold
in any Arizona gully.
He was sitting right there in the car
laughing like mad while he haunted me.
Well?
There was nothing I could say.
It was her move.
Vera or whatever her name was ...
It was just my luck, picking her up on the road.
Couldn t have been Helen or Mary or Evelyn or Ruth.
It had to be the very last person,
I should ever have met.
That s life.
Whichever way you turn,
fate sticks out a foot to trip you.
I told her everything,
but she didn t believe my story.
I should have saved my breath.
That s the greatest cock-and-bull story I ever heard.
So he fell out of his car? Say, who do you think
you re talking to? A hick?
Listen mister, I ve been around, and I know
a wrong guy when I see one.
What did you do? Kiss him with a wrench?
Now wait a minute, what I told you is true.
You see that s why I had to do it?
You think I killed him.
Well, the cops would have thought so too.
Yeah, well maybe they still think so.
What makes you so sure, I ll shut up about this.
Vera, I m innocent. Give me a break will you?
It won t do me any good having you fenced.
The cops are no friends of mine.
Now, if there was a reward ...
But there isn t.
Thanks.
Don t thank me yet, I m not through with you
by a long shot.
Let s see that roll.
Is that all Haskell had?
- Isn t it enough?
- No. I thought he had more.
Not that I know of. You can search me if you think
I m holding out on you.
Well, maybe I will at that.
He told me he was going to bet $3,000 ...
... on a horse named "Paradisical" on Wednesday
at Santa Anita.
- He was stringing you along. He meant $300.
- Maybe.
Sure, three bucks, three hundred.
He was a piece of cheese a big blowhard.
Listen mister, don t try and tell me anything about
Charlie Haskell.
Remember, I knew him better than you did.
OK, then you knew he was a four-flusher.
That explains the three grand bet.
I'm not so sure, he didn t have that three grand.
Why should I believe you?
You ve got all the earmarks of a cheap crook.
- Now wait a minute.
- Shut up.
You're a cheap crook and you killed him.
For two cents, I d change my mind and turn you in.
I don t like you.
- Alright alright, don t get sore.
- I m not getting sore.
But just remember who s boss around here.
If you shut up and don t give me any arguments
you ll have nothing to worry about.
But if you act wise ...
... I ll make sure you pop into jail so fast,
it'll give you the bends.
- I m not arguing.
- We see that you don t.
You know, as crooked as you look ...
... I hate to see a fella as young as you
wind up sniffing that perfume that ...
... Arizona hands out free to murderers.
- I'm not a murderer.
- Of course, you re not ...
Haskell knocked his own head off.
He fell, that's all, just like I told you.
Sure and then he made you a present of his belongings.
- I explained why I did that.
- Oh, skip it.
It doesn t make a difference one way or another.
I'm not a mourner.
I liked Haskell even less than I like you.
- Yeah, I saw what you did to him.
- What do you mean?
- The scratches on his wrist.
- Sure, I scratched him.
I ll say you did.
So your idea was to drive the car a little way ...
... maybe into San Bernardino and then leave it.
You weren t going to sell it?
Sell it? Do you think I'm crazy? Somebody else s car.
Yeah, all I want is to leave it somewhere
and forget I ever saw it.
Not only don t you have any scruples,
you don t have any brains.
I don t get you.
Maybe, it s a good thing you met me.
You d have got yourself caught, sure.
Why you dope.
Don t you know that a deserted
automobile always rates an investigation?
Huh?
Look, the cops find a car. Then they get curious.
They wonder where the owner is.
So all right, they don t trace Haskell.
They trace you.
I never thought of that.
The only safe way to get rid of the car
is to sell it to a dealer.
Get it registered under a new name.
Hey, stop at the next store. I want to get
a bottle and do some shopping ...
... before we hit L.A.
OK, if we find a place, I ll drop you off
and pick you up later.
Nothing doing. You re coming in too.
From now on, you and I are like the Siamese twins.
Have it your way, but I don t get the point.
The point is: I don t want you to get lost.
- I m not going to beat it, if that s what you're afraid of.
- I ll say you re not.
Why I m going to see you sell this car,
so you don t caught.
Thanks.
Course your interest wouldn t be financial, would it?
You wouldn t want a small percentage of the profits.
Well, now that you insist, how can I refuse.
- A hundred percent will do.
- Fine. I m relieved.
I thought for a moment, you were going to take it all.
I don t want to be a hog.
A few hours later, we were in Hollywood.
I was recognising places Sue had written about.
It struck me that far from being at
the end of the trip ...
... there was a greater distance between Sue and me
than when I started out.
Vera wasn t kidding with that  Siamese twins" crack.
She rented a little apartment ...
... as Mrs Charles Haskell.
When I objected to this, she explained
it was on account of the car.
The dealer might think something was funny,
if he called ...
... and found we were using different names.
- Home sweet home.
- Yeah.
Not bad either.
In case there is any doubt in your mind,
I ll take the bedroom.
Yep.
Sure is stuffy in here.
- Keep the windows shut.
- OK.
The old crow downstairs said there s a folding bed
behind this door.
You know how to work it?
I invented it.
- Some joint.
- One can t have everything.
I m first in the bathroom.
I don t know why, but I figured you would be.
Boy oh boy! It sure feels good to be clean again.
I must be 10 pounds lighter.
You must be.
Well that s alright. This is exactly the way
you keep your school book induction.
I wish that guy with the sax  would give up.
It gets on my nerves.
Forget it.
Have a drink.
Aren t you afraid I might take you up on it?
I didn t want to give you a drink,
I wouldn t have offered it.
I m very sorry, Roberts.
You got yourself into this thing.
You should be grateful, I m not turning you in.
Why if I wasn t regular, you d be in the pen this minute
being photographed ...
... finger-printed and being pushed around by the cops.
So cheer up. Get rid of that long puss.
Or is your conscience bothering you?
No.
- It isn t.
- Swell, that's good.
He's dead and no mooning around will bring him back.
Anyway, I never could understand this worrying about
something all been done with.
Now look, Vera, for the last time,
I didn t kill him.
Haskell was sick man. Maybe he was dead
before he fell out of the car. I don t know.
Sure, sure. He died of old age.
Alright ...
... so it ll make you sociable.
You didn t kill him.
Thanks.
- We re out of liquor, Roberts.
- Yeah.
Too bad, I felt like getting tight tonight.
- Well, I think you succeeded.
- Am I tight?
As a prima donna s corset.
That s good. I wanted to get tight.
Why? What have got to get tight about.
Oh, I don t know, a few things.
You should have my worries.
If I had your troubles, I d stay sober.
And I ve got the key to that door!
Yep.
- Maybe you're right.
- I m always right.
You know, I don t like your attitude, Roberts.
Well, there s a lot of things I don t like.
Sure is.
Life s like a ball game, you got to take
a swing at whatever comes along ...
... before you wake up and find it s the ninth innings.
- You read that somewhere.
- That's the problem with you, Roberts.
All you do is bellyache
I m taking it easy, and trying to make
the best of things.
Maybe that's what wrong with the whole world.
It s a profession.
People knock themselves out trying to bust fate.
Now take you, for instance.
You're lucky to be alive.
Why, supposing Haskell had opened your door.
You d be playing a harp, now.
Think of that.
You think of it. I m tired of thinking.
There s plenty of people dying this minute ...
... would give anything to trade places with you.
I know what I'm talking about.
I'm not so sure.
At least, they know they re done for.